# David A. Curtis

# Development Big Pixel, LLC

April 2014 to Present

Ruby on Rails | Mobile App Developer

<u>Summary:</u> I am responsible for the full-stack development of Rails and hybrid mobile applications. I also create RESTful APIs; handle domain modeling and application architecture; as well as QA for all projects. Aside from my boss who owns the company, I am the senior developer, which means I am frequently given customer specs and told to 'build it', with very little guidance or assistance. I have also lead the integration of new tools and technologies into our workflow, such as PhoneGap, AngularJS, many APIs (ex: Facebook), Amazon S3, and of course Rails, to name a few.

Skills: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, CoffeeScript, Haml, Sass, LESS, MongoDB (NoSQL), SQL, AJAX, JSON, Material Design, Bootstrap, HTML5/CSS3, Jade, APIs (such as Facebook, Foursquare, Leaflet, Mapbox, open data sources), Swift/iOS. Tools include: Sublime, PhoneGap, Slack, pgAdmin, Bower/Grunt, Amazon S3, Vis. Studio, Xcode, Google Dev. Tools, Prepos, PhotoShop, others.

Sample Projects (Code samples provided upon request)

**Mevii:** Mevii is a hybrid (PhoneGap) mobile application that I built from the ground up. It has been about an eight month project, so far. Learn more at mevii.com, and you can find it in the app stores by searching 'Mevii'. I built most of the front-end (Jade, JS, Sass), and contributed to the ASP.NET API.

**Swaggr:** Swaggr is composed of three separate Rails applications: the customer-facing front-end, an API, and an Admin portal. Although it is about to launch in private beta, it may currently be viewed at gotswaggr.com. Swaggr is an online platform where clothing stylists will help men select clothes. I built the entire API, have handled most of the front-end and email integration, and have contributed significantly to the admin portal.

## **Tech Talent South (Code Immersion Program)**

June 2014 to July 2014

Assistant Instructor (Ruby on Rails | Web App Development): Part-time

# Other Experience

#### Modis, Raleigh, NC

Jan. 2012 to Mar. 2014

## **Executive Recruiter: IT and Healthcare**

- IT recruiting nationally for many highly sought after skill sets, including: .NET, Java, and SQL
  Developers; Network Engineers; Operations Managers; Tech Writers; Health Care Professionals; and
  other IT and non-IT industry professionals for contract and direct hire opportunities
- Excelled in locating passive candidates using non-traditional techniques (going beyond job boards)
- Account management: built relationships with hiring managers, assisted them throughout the hiring cycle from start to finish; identified client needs and developed hiring plans

#### U.S. Dept. of Justice, U.S. Attorney's Office, Raleigh, NC

July 2010 to Nov. 2011

## Paralegal Specialist, Criminal Division, GS-950-9, TOP SECRET SECURITY CLEARANCE

- Case management of major investigation and indictment of politician: identified and located former
  campaign staff and potential witnesses; generated investigative leads; developed and recommended
  courses of action; researched complex campaign finance laws and FEC opinions; analyzed and
  digested law enforcement reports; acted as liaison between USAO, FBI, and IRS; oversight,
  organization, and storage of 400,000 documents; developed and maintained evidentiary and
  subpoena logs; coordinated witness travel
- Provided research and writing support to Criminal Division Assistant U.S. Attorneys, including: drafting briefs, responses, motions, proposed orders, and other pleadings

- Served as District's FOIA (Freedom of Information Act) Coordinator; served as back-up Public Information Officer; served as mentor to new legal assistants; reviewed all Criminal Division judgments for potential appellate issues
- Used LEXIS, Westlaw, Courtlink, law enforcement databases for legal research and investigative purposes; participated in the investigation and prosecution of complex crimes

U.S. Dept. of Justice, U.S. Attorney's Office, Raleigh, NC

July 2009 to June 2010

U.S. Dept. of Justice, U.S. Attorney's Office, Augusta, GA

May 2008 to July 2009

#### Legal Assistant, Criminal Division, GS-986-7, TOP SECRET SECURITY CLEARANCE

- Prepared search and arrest warrants, affidavits, writs, production orders, grand jury and trial subpoenas, trial exhibits, and correspondence
- Caseload experience included campaign finance violations; tax evasion and fraud; securities and mortgage fraud; identity theft; cases involving guns, drugs, gangs; other violent crimes
- Safeguarded sensitive information daily, including: grand jury materials, wiretaps, pen registers, ongoing and undercover operations, cooperating witnesses, and tax records

Uline, Inc., Duluth, GA

Aug. 2005 to Feb. 2007

#### Inside Sales (Quotes Dept.), Customer Service

- Assisted customers with special pricing requests, returns, warranty issues, and tracing shipments
- Established and maintained relationships with vendors and customers nationwide
- Processed customer orders via phone and internet (averaged 145-165 per day)
- Answered product, pricing, and availability inquiries; helped customers resolve invoicing issues

RE/MAX, Myers Team Realty, Loganville, GA

Nov. 2001 to July 2005

Realtor, Manager (New Home Sales Division)

Williams & Connolly, LLP, Washington, DC

Dec. 1998 to June 2000

**Paralegal** 

The White House, Office of Political Affairs, Washington, DC

Jan. 1998 to May 1998

#### Staff Assistant to the Chief of Staff

- Responsible for writing six sections of the weekly political briefing for principals and senior staff (including: President, Vice President, and Cabinet); political research and analysis
- Researched and drafted travel briefings for the President, Vice President, and First Lady
- Drafted letters to political leaders and constituents for the President and First Lady

#### **Education**

The American University, Washington, DC

Bachelor of Arts, Political Science (Dec. 1999)

Wake Tech, Raleigh, NC

Web Development Track (2011-2013; 4.0 GPA)

Tech Talent South, Raleigh, NC

Ruby on Rails | Web Development Code Immersion Program (Early 2014)

Honors

**Phi Theta Kappa Scholar** (1997, 1998, 1999)

National Dean's List (1997) Political Science Award (1997)